OK, hello, welcome back.
好的 大家好 欢迎回来
Sorry about all the chaos last time.
上次混乱的事情真是抱歉
Hopefully, it's not as chaotic today.
希望今天不会那么乱
If you're just coming in, there's more seats over on this side.
如果你刚刚进来 这边还有更多座位
So please walk across to the other entrance.
所以请走到另一边的入口
Raise your hand if you have a seat next to you that's open.
如果你旁边有空座位 请举手
Yeah, have a seat over there.
是的 请在那边坐下
No seats over here.
这边没座位了
Apparently, people would just like that entrance specifically.
显然 人们只想去那个入口
OK, let's get started.
好的 我们开始吧
Welcome back.
欢迎回来
So today, we get to talk all about defining and using classes.
今天 我们要谈谈如何定义和使用类
I hope you're excited.
希望你很兴奋
So let's jump right into IntelliJ, which is our programming platform of choice.
那么 让我们马上进入 IntelliJ 这是我们选择的编程平台
Hopefully, you'll set it up in Lab 1.
希望你能在实验1中设置好它
And so we will start by defining a method for dogs.
我们将从为狗定义一个方法开始
So I'll say public static, oops, make noise.
我会说public static 哎呀 发出声音
And I'll make it say bark.
我会让它说汪汪
OK, so oops.
好的 哎呀
What happened this time?
这次发生了什么
I forgot to write a return value.
我忘记写返回值了
So makeNoise doesn't return anything.
所以 makeNoise 不返回任何东西
So this says dogs say bark.
这里说狗会叫汪汪
OK.
好的
Now, what if I want to have a dog actually say bark?
现在 如果我想让一只狗真的叫汪汪呢
Well, I could say public static void main.
嗯 我可以说 public static void main
We know that's where code goes, because all code has to live in a class.
我们知道那是代码放的地方 因为所有的代码都必须放在一个类里面
And now I can say makeNoise.
然后我可以说 makeNoise
And hopefully what happens when I run this is my dog will go bark eventually, soon.
希望我运行这个时 我的狗最终会叫 很快的
If people are coming in, find a seat.
如果有人进来 找个座位
Aha!
啊哈！
OK, that was not expected.
好的 这是出乎意料的
OK.
好的
OK, this is the stuff you'll finish in Lab 1, I'm sure.
好的 这些是你会在实验1中完成的内容 我确定
Unlike me, apparently.
显然不像我
So if you fix that, and I try again, I will have my dog go bark for you any minute now.
如果你修复了那个问题 然后我再试一次 我马上让我的狗为你叫一声
Really?
真的吗
OK.
好的
I forgot to comment that out.
我忘记把那段注释掉了
Sorry, hectic day.
抱歉 今天太忙了
I also have to set up a new part of today's lecture, brand new just for you.
我还得为今天的讲座设置一个新部分 专门为你准备的全新内容
What else does it want?
它还想要什么
OK, try one more time.
好的 再试一次
We can edit this out in post later, right, so people don't see it?
后期可以剪掉这部分 对吧 这样观众就看不到了
OK.
好的
Raise your hand if you have a seat next to you still.
如果你旁边还有座位 就举手
OK, seat's over here.
好的 座位在这边
People who just left, no.
刚离开的人 不行
OK.
好的
That's all right.
没问题
So our dog went bark after a little bit of setup issues.
所以在一点设置问题后 我们的狗就开始叫了
Our dog has gone bark.
我们的狗已经叫了
That's great.
太好了
But sometimes we might want to have the dog go bark from a different class.
但有时候我们可能希望狗是从另一个类开始叫的
So here, instead of having the dog go bark in the dog class, I could create a different class called DogLauncher.
在这里 我可以创建一个叫做DogLauncher的不同类 而不是让狗在狗类中开始叫
So every dog ought to be launched.
所以每只狗都应该被启动
And in my DogLauncher class, I can have a main method.
在我的DogLauncher类中 我可以有一个main方法
That's where my code outside of a function lives.
这是我的函数之外的代码所在的地方
And instead of just saying make noise here, I'm actually going to write dog. .makeNoise.
而不只是说在这里制造噪音 我实际上要写dog.makeNoise()
And the reason why I have to say dog.makeNoise is because the makeNoise method, it doesn't live in the DogLogic class.
我必须说dog.makeNoise的原因是因为makeNoise方法不在DogLogic类中
It lives in the Dog class.
它在Dog类中
So I say, go to the Dog class, find the makeNoise method, and call the makeNoise method.
所以我说 在Dog类 找到makeNoise方法 然后调用makeNoise方法
So now if I run this, I get Bark again.
现在如果我运行这个 我再次得到Bark
But this time, I'm calling it from a different class.
但是这次 我是从一个不同的类中调用它
This is really nice because being able to split up my complicated code into different classes is how I'm going to be able to take really complicated programs and decompose them into smaller pieces.
这真的很好 因为能够将我的复杂代码拆分成不同的类是我能够将非常复杂的程序分解成较小部分的方法
So let's reflect on what just happened.
让我们反思一下刚刚发生的事情
So as we saw from last time, every method has to be in a class.
正如我们上次看到的 每个方法都必须在一个类中
All code has to be in a class.
所有的代码都必须在一个类中
And if I want to run a program, I have to have a main method.
如果我想运行一个程序 我必须有一个主方法
And when I run that program, the main method is what gets executed.
当我运行那个程序时 主方法就会被执行
And something you'll notice is that when I took the main method out of Dog and put it into DogLauncher, now this Dog class no longer has a main method, and I can't run it.
有件事你会注意到 就是当我把主方法从Dog类中拿出来放到DogLauncher中时 现在这个Dog类就不再有主方法了 我也无法运行它
Look, the intelligence environment is like, there's no green arrow.
看 智能环境就像 没有绿色的箭头
You can't run this program anymore because there's no more main.
你不能再运行这个程序了 因为没有主方法了
But that's OK.
但没关系
I can still run the main method in DogLauncher.
我仍然可以在DogLauncher中运行主方法
OK, my first demo of the day.
好的 今天的第一个演示
Good so far?
目前还不错吧
Questions?
有问题吗
Anything else broken?
还有其他东西坏了吗
OK.
好的
Question back there?
那边有问题吗
Where is it?
在哪里
You have to, like, wave aggressively.
你必须 嗯 用力挥动
Left.
左边
Hi.
嗨
Yeah.
是的
Oh, yes.
哦 是的
Zoom in.
放大
That's a great point.
这是一个很好的观点
Let's do it.
让我们做吧
View.
查看
I hope it's in here.
希望它在这里
Justin, how do I zoom in?
贾斯汀 我怎么放大
Is it not in view?
不在视野里吗
Aha.
啊哈
Increase font size.
增大字体大小
OK.
好的
I increase.
我增加
Tell me when.
告诉我什么时候
I increase.
我增加
Are we good?
我们好吗
OK, well, that's OK.
好的 那就好
What is it? One more?
这是什么 再来一个吗
Oh, OK.
哦 好的
What is the hotkey?
热键是什么
It's control, shift, dot.
是 control shift 点
OK.
好的
How much more do you want?
你还想要多少
How's that?
怎么样
I think that's good.
我觉得那挺好的
OK.
好的
Yeah, I don't think we need to make it much bigger.
我觉得我们不需要再做得更大了
OK, beautiful.
好的 很不错
OK, so we did a dog demo.
好的 我们做了一个狗的演示
We went bark.
我们走吧 汪汪
We made the text larger.
我们把文字变大了
All sorts of good stuff.
各种好东西
But there's one problem, which is not all dogs are created equal.
但有一个问题 就是并非所有的狗都是平等的
So for example, and I hope this audio works, here's a dog on the left.
例如 希望这个音频有效 这是左边的一只狗
Oh no, there's no audio.
哦不 没有音频
Justin, where's my audio?
贾斯汀 我的音频在哪
Let's see. It is going to everyone.
让我们看看  它要传给每个人
OK, I'm going to try it one more time.
好的 我再试一次
There's no audio.
没有音频
No, there is audio.
不 有音频
So how do I get it to the people in person?
那我怎么把它传给人们呢
I want the people in person to hear this.
我想让人们亲自听到这个
OK, that doesn't sound very exciting.
好的 这听起来不是很令人兴奋
So Justin, where's the audio?
Justin 音频在哪
I told you we should have done it the way we used to do it.
我告诉过你我们应该按照过去的方式做
It's not fine.
不好了
这不好
I want to hear this part.
我想听这一部分
OK, I'll play it, and Justin will do the audio for us today.
好的 我会播放 今天Justin负责音频
OK, so not all dogs are created equal.
好的 所以并非所有的狗都是平等的
For example, this great Alaskan Malamute makes this sound.
例如 这只了不起的阿拉斯加雪橇犬发出了这种声音
Oh, shoot.
哦 该死
OK, thank you, Justin.
好的 谢谢 贾斯汀
Beautiful bark.
漂亮的吠声
OK.
好的
Ooh, beautiful roo.
哦 漂亮的袋鼠
OK.
好的
By contrast, this dog on the right, it makes this sound.
相比之下 右边的这只狗 它发出这种声音
Thank you, Justin.
谢谢 Justin
OK.
好的
All of this is to say different dogs make different sounds.
所有这些都是为了说不同的狗会发出不同的声音
So when we write methods and classes, we often want to model features of the real world.
当我们编写方法和类时 我们经常想要模拟现实世界的特征
So maybe we want different dogs to bark differently.
也许我们希望不同的狗有不同的叫声
So for example, one way I could maybe model this is to say, well, some dogs, like Maya the dog, they'll make this a roo sound.
例如 我可能会这样建模 一些狗 像Maya这只狗 它们会发出这种声音
But then other dogs like Yapster the dog.
但其他狗狗们都像Yapster一样
I don't know that dog's name, but we'll call it Yapster.
我不知道那只狗的名字 但我们就叫它Yapster吧
It makes this hideous sound on the right.
它在右边发出这种可怕的声音
So I can make a different class for every dog, but this is going to get redundant really quickly.
所以我可以为每只狗狗创建一个不同的类 但这样会很快变得冗余
So I want to find a better solution.
我想找到一个更好的解决方案
And the better solution is something we kind of saw last time, but we'll make very explicit this time, which is that classes can contain not just code, but also data.
而更好的解决方案其实是我们上次看到的那种 但这次我们会非常明确地表达 那就是类不仅可以包含代码 还可以包含数据
So what do I mean by that?
那么我是什么意思呢
Let's go in here, and let's give dog an instance variable.
咱们进这里 给狗狗加个实例变量
So now every instance of a dog can have a different value for its instance variable.
这样 每个狗狗的实例都可以有一个不同的值作为它的实例变量
The variable I'm going to choose is an integer called weight in pounds.
我要选择的变量是一个叫做weight_in_pounds的整数
So this is going to tell me how much does each dog that I create weigh.
这会告诉我每只我创建的狗狗有多重
And when I create different dogs, they can have different weights in pounds.
当我创建不同的狗狗时 它们可以有不同的重量（以磅为单位）
Weight in pounds. So now what I can do is I can say, you know what?
以磅为单位的重量  那么现在我可以说 你知道吗
Not all dogs go bark.
并非所有的狗都会叫
In fact, the way that a dog goes bark depends on how much it weighs.
实际上 一只狗发出声音的方式取决于它的重量
So I could say, if the weight in pounds is less than 10, it's a very small dog.
我可以说 如果以磅为单位的重量小于10 那是一只非常小的狗
So maybe I'll have it say, you know, yip, yip, yip.
也许我会让它发出像是 你知道的 汪汪汪的声音
OK, so it's a very small dog.
好的 所以这是一只非常小的狗
But what if the dog is a little bit larger?
但如果狗稍微大一些呢
So what if the weight in pounds is less than, say, 30?
那么如果以磅为单位的重量小于 比如说 30呢
OK, then maybe it's like a medium-sized dog.
好吧 也许就像一只中等大小的狗
And I'll have it say bark.
然后我让它叫一声汪汪
And then otherwise, if it's even larger than 30, it's such a big dog that it's going to have that majestic roo sound from earlier.
否则 如果它的体型超过30 那么它就是一只如此巨大的狗 它会发出之前那种威严的嗥叫声
So now I have this makeNoise method do something different depending on the dog that I pass in, or the dog that's calling the makeNoise method.
现在我有了这个 makeNoise 方法 根据我传入的狗 或者调用 makeNoise 方法的狗 做一些不同的事情
But there's a little problem, which is it's complaining.
但是有一个小问题 就是它在抱怨
Java IntelliJ has all these red symbols.
Java IntelliJ 上有所有这些红色符号
And it says, non-static field cannot be referenced from a static context.
它说 非静态字段无法从静态上下文引用
kind of mysterious.
有点神秘
So the fix, not that it's immediately obvious, but the fix that we're going to use is we're going to delete the word static.
所以解决方案 虽然并不是立即显而易见的 但我们要使用的解决方案是删除单词static
And suddenly...
突然间...
Okay, can people on Zoom hear like this?
好的 Zoom上的人们能听到吗
There's a bit of echo.
有点回音
It's kind of awkward.
有点尴尬
Why is there an echo if there's microphone?
如果有麦克风 为什么会有回音呢
That's not intended.
这不是故意的
Next time we are not using the Zoom infrastructure anymore.
下次我们不再使用 Zoom 基础设施了
It's so complicated.
这太复杂了
Okay.
好的
Okay, everyone has to be super silent so that people on Zoom can hear without the static.
每个人都要保持超级安静 这样 Zoom 上的人就可以听到声音而不会有静音声
Okay.
好的
Can I go back to when I remove static?
我能回去当我去掉静音时吗
Apparently, okay, I'll go back to when I remove static.
显然 好的 我会回到我删除静态的时候
So I add the word static.
所以我加上了static这个词
Why am I hearing myself on Echo?
为什么我在Echo上听到自己的声音
I don't know, I muted that.
我不知道 我把声音调了
Oh, wait.
哦 等等
Justin, Justin.
Justin Justin
How's the mic working? Did you turn off the mic?
麦克风怎么样 你关掉麦克风了吗
What do you mean, did I turn off the mic?
你是说 我关掉了麦克风吗
Did you turn off the mic?
你关掉麦克风了吗
Oh, I see, you want me to turn this thing off entirely?
我明白了 你是想让我完全把这个东西关掉
Yeah.
是的
Okay.
好的
Okay, how about that?
好的 那样怎么样
Now I can't hear myself?
现在我听不到自己了
Yeah, there.
是的 在那里
Okay, I guess it wasn't, like, totally dead.
好的 我想它不是完全没声音的
Okay.
好的
Yeah, it wasn't totally dead.
是的 它不是完全没声音的
Okay, everyone's got to be extremely quiet so the people on Zoom can actually hear me, and the people in the back can actually hear me.
好的 大家要非常安静 这样Zoom上的人才能听到我 后面的人才能听到我
Okay, I'm gonna, like, wait.
好的 我要等一下
Why can't I still hear myself?
为什么我还听得到自己呢
What do you mean?
你是什么意思
Okay, maybe not.
好吧 也许不行
All right.
好的
Okay, we'll give it a shot, and we'll see what happens.
好的 我们试试看 看看会发生什么
I still feel like I can hear myself, though, unless I'm, like, hallucinating.
但我还是觉得我能听到自己 除非我在幻觉中
No?
不是吗
Okay, I'll leave it as is.
好的 我就这么保留了
All right, let's keep going.
好的 我们继续
So, I had the word static,
所以 我有一个static这个词
I got rid of it, and the dog class is now happy.
我把它去掉了 dog类现在很开心了
OK.
好的
However, there's still a problem on this side, which is that I still feel like I'm hearing myself, Justin.
但是 这边还有个问题 就是我还觉得我在听我自己 Justin
Why?
为什么
There's no echo online, but there's an echo in person.
在网上没有回声 但现场有回声
What?
什么
Yeah.
是的
Okay, I guess I'll have to keep talking and I'll have to like listen to myself.
好吧 我想我得继续说话 我得像倾听自己一样
It's a little, it's a little trippy, but hopefully we'll live with it.
有点 有点迷幻 但希望我们能应付过来
And then Justin will do some tech support while we wait.
然后 Justin 在我们等待时会进行一些技术支持
Okay.
好的
Yeah, I guess.
是的 我想是吧
Okay.
好的
It's day three of class and I'm already losing my mind.
上课第三天了 我已经快要疯了
Okay.
好的
As I was saying before I was so rudely interrupted, we had the word static, Java was complaining, the fix wasn't super obvious, but I deleted the word static, and at least the Dog class is okay now.
就像我之前被粗鲁地打断一样 我们遇到了 static 这个词 Java 抱怨了 修复并不是很明显 但我删除了 static 这个词 至少 Dog 类现在没问题了
However, there's still a problem on the Dog launcher side, and specifically on the Dog launcher side, it says, oops, forgot the word if.
然而 在 Dog 启动器这一侧仍然存在问题 具体来说 在 Dog 启动器这一侧 它说 哎呀 忘了加 if 这个词
The Dog Launcher site, it says, non-static method cannot be referenced from a static context.
在 Dog 启动器网站上 它说 非静态方法无法从静态上下文中引用
And again, you might be tempted to delete the word static.
再说一次 你可能会想要删除 static 这个词
Turns out that is not the solution here.
事实证明这里并不是解决方案
The solution here is we actually need a specific dog to make noise.
这里的解决方案是 实际上我们需要一个特定的狗发出声音
So this line of code is saying something like, how do dogs make noise?
这行代码的意思是 狗怎么发出声音呢
It's a general purpose question about all dogs.
这是一个关于所有狗的通用问题
But you can see here the makeNoise method, it expects a specific dog to make noise because it's asking about a specific dog's weight in pounds.
但是你可以看到这里的 makeNoise 方法 它期望一个特定的狗发出声音 因为它询问的是特定狗的体重（以磅为单位）
So to fix this, I'm going to actually create an instance of a dog.
为了解决这个问题 我将创建一个狗的实例
This is new syntax that we just briefly saw from last time.
这是我们上次简要介绍的新语法
So I'll say dogD equals new dog.
所以我会说dog d=new Dog
And I'll say, there it is.
然后我会说 就是这样
That creates a brand new dog.
这创造了一只全新的狗
Then I'll say, this new dog has a weight in pounds of, well, let's make it 20 pounds.
然后我会说 这只新狗的体重是20磅
And then now, instead of dog.makeNoise, which says, how do all dogs make noise?
现在 不再使用dog.makeNoise 它表示 所有狗都会发出什么样的噪音
I'm going to say d.makeNoise.
我会说d.makeNoise
And that's such a subtle difference, but it's going to make a big difference in how we write this code.
这是一个微妙的差别 但在我们编写这段代码时会产生很大的影响
So now, because I have d.makeNoise, the code is compiling.
现在 因为我有了 d.makeNoise 代码正在编译
And when I run DogLauncher, I will get my 20-pound dog barking, and it says, bark.
当我运行 DogLauncher 时 我会听到我的 20 磅重的狗叫 它会说 汪汪
And if I change this to be like 100 pounds, a very big dog, then it should give me the whole aroo sound.
如果我将这个改成像 100 磅的 一个非常大的狗 那么它应该给我整个吼叫的声音
By the way, can we get the settings
顺便问一下 我们能不能获取这些设置
Out of the projection, Justin, tech support.
Justin 技术支持 幻灯片之外
OK, thank you.
好的 谢谢
OK, so if I change the weight in pounds to 100, I get the beautiful aroo sound from before.
好的 如果我将重量从磅变为100 我就能听到之前那美妙的“啊呜”声
So the main difference is, instead of having the question, how do all dogs make noise?
主要的区别在于 不再是提出问题 所有狗都是怎么发出声音的
I have the question, I have a specific dog.
我有个问题 我有一只特定的狗
Its weight in pounds is 100. How does it make noise?
它的重量是100磅  它是怎么发出声音的
OK, one final little fix I'll make is, if you're familiar with object-oriented programming, you might recognize that setting instance variables like this is not super common.
好的 我会做一个最后的小修正 如果你熟悉面向对象编程 你可能会认识到像这样设置实例变量并不是很常见的
And in fact, the more common approach is to write the constructor, kind of like what we saw last time.
事实上 更常见的方法是编写构造函数 有点像我们上次看到的那样
And we'll say this constructor, which is a blueprint for how to create brand new dogs, it's going to take in an argument.
我们会说这个构造函数 它是如何创建全新狗狗的蓝图 它将接受一个参数
And then we'll set the weight in pounds equal to that argument.
然后我们将磅重设为该参数
So now when I create the new dog, I can directly pass in that it's a hundred pound dog, and I asked the dog to make noise, and it gives me the beautiful roo sound from earlier.
现在当我创建新狗时 我可以直接传入它是一只一百磅的狗 然后我要求狗发出声音 它会给我之前听到的美丽的嗥叫声
Okay, let's reflect on what happened.
好的 让我们回顾一下发生了什么
Maybe not the technical difficulty part, but the Java part.
也许不是技术难度部分 而是 Java 部分
OK, so we saw that classes can contain not just functions and the methods, but also data.
好的 所以我们看到类不仅可以包含函数和方法 还可以包含数据
So we added the weight and pounds variable.
我们添加了重量和磅变量
And then instead of just calling dog.makeNoise, we created specific dogs.
然后 不再只是调用dog.makeNoise 我们创建了具体的dogs
And then we had the specific dogs make noise.
然后 我们让这些具体的dogs发出声音
So here's the code from before.
这是之前的代码
If you're curious about the Python version, it's there on the slides.
如果你对Python版本感兴趣 它就在幻灯片上
OK, that's a lot of stuff that I just went through.
好的 我刚刚讲解了很多东西
So let's go through some terms to make sure we can all talk about this using the same language.
那么让我们通过一些术语来确保我们都能用相同的语言谈论这个
So what did we just see?
那么我们刚刚看到了什么
Well, we saw that I created an instance variable in the dog class.
嗯 我们看到我在狗类中创建了一个实例变量
This is like an attribute of all dogs.
这就像所有狗的属性一样
So I can say every dog that I create has its own weight in pounds.
我可以说 我创建的每只狗都有自己的体重（以磅为单位）
OK, but then we saw that I wrote a constructor.
好的 但接着我们看到我写了一个构造函数
That's like the blueprint for how to create new dogs.
那就像创建新狗的蓝图一样
It's a special method that I can write.
这是我可以编写的一个特殊方法
It has the same name as the class.
它的名称与类相同
And that's how I create brand new dogs.
这就是我创造全新狗的方式
Here, when I create a brand new dog, all that I have to do is set its weight in pounds.
在这里 当我创建一个全新的狗时 我所需要做的就是设置它的重量（以磅为单位）
But you could also set up dogs in other ways if your dog has other properties.
但是如果你的狗有其他属性 你也可以以其他方式设置狗
So maybe your dog also has a height.
也许你的狗还有身高
It has number of legs.
它有几条腿
It has favorite food, favorite city in Italy, whatever you want.
它有最喜欢的食物 最喜欢的意大利城市 任何你想要的
Dogs can have other instance variables too.
狗也可以有其他实例变量
Finally, we had this makeNoise method.
最后 我们有了这个 makeNoise 方法
And when I removed the word static, what happened is that this method is now an instance method.
当我去掉 static 这个词时 发生的是这个方法现在是一个实例方法
So instead of asking a question like, how do dogs make noise?
所以 不再问类似于 狗怎么制造噪音的问题了
That's a question that's general purpose to all dogs ever.
这是一个对所有狗普遍存在的问题
I now have a method that says, this specific dog, Maya the dog, make your noise, or Yapster the dog, make your noise.
现在我有一个方法说 这个特定的狗 玛雅狗 发出你的声音 或者雅普斯特狗 发出你的声音
And roughly speaking, if this isn't totally sinking in, one way you can think about this makeNoise method when it's non-static is it has to reference my weight in pounds.
大致上来说 如果这还没完全明白 你可以这样想 当这个 makeNoise 方法是非静态的时候 它必须引用我的体重（以磅为单位）
There's a mean.
有一个均值
So when I read this function, I have to say something like, when my weight in pounds is less than 10, then yip, yip, yip.
当我阅读这个函数时 我必须说一些类似的东西 当我的体重以磅为单位少于10时 然后汪汪汪
When my weight in pounds is less than 30, then bark, bark.
当我的体重以磅为单位少于30时 然后汪汪
So because I have to reference a mean, I have to create an instance of the dog variable to use it.
因为我必须引用一个平均值 我必须创建一个狗变量的实例来使用它
So this method has to be non-static.
这个方法必须是非静态的
So that's just some vocabulary that you might see.
那只是你可能会看到的一些词汇
as we go through the class.
当我们浏览这个类时
OK.
好的
Questions?
有问题吗
Do I have to be louder?
我需要大声一点吗
Any other technical difficulties?
还有其他技术难题吗
OK.
好的
Great.
太好了
So this is all stuff we've seen before.
所以这些都是我们以前看过的东西
We said that classes can be instantiated.
我们说过类可以被实例化
So now, when I create or when I want to call this makeNoise method, I have to create a brand new dog.
现在 当我创建或想要调用这个 makeNoise 方法时 我必须创建一个全新的狗
I have to set its weight in pounds.
我必须设置它的重量（单位为磅）
And then I can ask it to make noise.
然后我就可以要求它发出声音了
OK.
好的
Great.
太棒了
Here's a little bit more vocabulary, and then I'm done with the vocabulary for the day.
这是一点更多的词汇 然后我今天的词汇就结束了
So what was the syntax for creating a brand new dog?
那么创建一个全新的狗的语法是什么
Let's drill into this just a little bit more.
让我们再深入了解一下这个问题
So we saw that when I create a new dog, a couple of things actually happened.
因此我们看到 当我创建一个新的狗时 实际上发生了几件事
First, I had to declare that there is a variable of type small dog, and it's of type dog.
首先 我必须声明有一个类型为小狗的变量 它的类型是狗
So the name of the variable is small dog.
因此变量的名称是小狗
It's of type dog, because in Java, before I use a variable, I first have to declare that the variable exists.
它的类型是狗 因为在Java中 我使用变量之前 我首先必须声明变量的存在
So this line of code, it declares there is a variable called small dog.
因此这行代码 它声明了有一个叫做小狗的变量
Something else that I did was I wrote this special keyword new, which we'll see again next time.
我做的另一件事是我写了一个特殊的关键字new 我们下次再见
And this keyword with the constructor, this was how I instantiated, which is a fancy way of saying I created a brand new dog from scratch.
通过构造函数使用这个关键字 这就是我实例化的方式 也就是说我从头开始创建了一个全新的狗
So there used to not be a dog.
所以以前没有狗
When I say new dog, a brand new dog object was created from scratch.
当我说新狗时 是指从头创建了一个全新的狗对象
But the problem with the second line is that I haven't actually saved the dog anywhere.
但第二行的问题在于 我实际上并没有将狗保存在任何地方
It's never been assigned to a variable.
它从未被分配给一个变量
So because this dog has been created, but there's no reference to it, it's going to get destroyed by the garbage collector.
因此 由于这只狗已经被创建 但没有引用它 它将被垃圾收集器销毁
Very scary term.
非常可怕的术语
So that's what happens if you instantiate and create a dog object, but you don't assign it to any variable.
这就是如果你实例化并创建一个狗对象 但不将它分配给任何变量会发生的情况
By contrast, if you look at this next line, here I am instantiating and saying, let me create a brand new dog of size 5 from nowhere, but let me also assign it to the smallDog variable.
相比之下 如果你看看接下来的这一行 我在这里实例化并说 让我从无处创建一个尺寸为5的全新狗 但也让我将它分配给smallDog变量
So now this dog can be referred to by its new name, which is smallDog.
所以现在这只狗可以用它的新名字来引用 也就是smallDog
Finally, sometimes you'll do all of this together.
最后 有时你会把所有这些都做在一起
So this is the line of code we had before.
这是我们之前有的那行代码
And it's actually doing three things, even though it doesn't seem like it's doing so many things.
实际上它在做三件事情 尽管看起来似乎没有做那么多事情
So what am I doing here?
那么我在这里做什么呢
I am first declaring there is a variable called hugeDog, dog hugeDog.
首先 我声明有一个叫做hugeDog的变量 是个狗 就是hugeDog
Then I am creating a brand new Dog object by saying new Dog 150.
然后 我通过说new Dog 150来创建一个全新的Dog对象
And finally, I'm assigning this brand new Dog that I've created to the variable called hugeDog.
最后 我将这个我刚刚创建的全新Dog对象赋给了叫做hugeDog的变量
And now that I've done that, my dogs can make noise.
现在 我完成了这些 我的狗可以发出声音了
So just a bit of vocabulary.
所以就是一点词汇
When you see a line like this, you are declaring the variable, you are creating the new object, and then you're assigning the new object to the variable you just declared.
当你看到这样的一行时 你是在声明变量 创建新对象 然后将新对象赋给你刚刚声明的变量
Sound good?
听起来不错吧
All right.
好的
There's a quick note on arrays in case you need it for project zero, but there's a video on it, and we're probably way behind because of all that time I spent hallucinating, so I'll just skip over it for now.
关于数组有个简短的说明 如果你在零号项目中需要的话 但已经有相关的视频了 由于我花了很多时间在幻觉中 我们可能已经落后了 所以我暂时跳过它
Okay.
好的
Great, so let's dig in even more.
太好了 让我们深入了解一下
This static thing is understandably a little bit confusing, so I'll talk about it just a little bit more.
这个静态的东西可能有点令人困惑 我会再多讲一点
So what is the difference between having a static method and a non-static method?
那么拥有静态方法和非静态方法有什么区别呢
What does this word actually mean?
这个词实际上是什么意思呢
So the way I think of it is, when your method is static, this method is general purpose to all dogs.
我想的方式是 当你的方法是静态的时候 这个方法是通用的 适用于所有狗
It's like a question about all dogs.
就像是关于所有狗的一个问题
So if I had to describe this method, I would say something like, how do dogs make noise?
如果我要描述这个方法 我会说类似于 狗怎么会发出声音呢
It's a question about all dogs and not any specific dog.
这是一个关于所有狗而不是任何特定狗的问题
In order to use the static method, I will invoke it using the class name like we saw from before.
为了使用静态方法 我将像之前看到的那样使用类名来调用它
So I'll say DogClass, the blueprint for dogs.
我会说 DogClass 狗的蓝图
Please tell me how dogs make noise.
请告诉我狗怎么发声
By contrast, if I have a non-static method, the non-static method is specific to one dog.
相比之下 如果我有一个非静态方法 那么非静态方法就是针对一个狗的
So this might be something like, Maya, how do you make noise?
这可能是这样的 玛雅 你怎么发出声音
Or Yapster the dog, how do you make noise?
或者是狗耶普斯特 你怎么发出声音
And this is specific to a dog because you'll notice that it's referencing its own instance variable.
这是针对一个狗的 因为你会注意到它引用了自己的实例变量
So here we have to say, if my weight in pounds is less than 10, me, Maya, if my weight in pounds is less than 10, then yip, yip, yip.
在这里我们必须说 如果我的体重以磅为单位小于10 那么我 玛雅 如果我的体重以磅为单位小于10 那么就汪汪叫
And how do I use this non-static method?
那么我怎么使用这个非静态方法呢
I can no longer say, how do dogs make noise?
我不能再说 狗怎么发出声音
Because I'm asking about a specific dog.
因为我在问一个特定的狗
So I have to say, there is a brand new dog called Maya, and Maya make your noise.
所以我得说 有一只全新的狗叫做玛雅 而玛雅会发出声音
And then Maya will go, in this case, woof.
然后玛雅会叫 这种情况下 汪汪叫
So when I add the word static, it's general purpose to all dogs.
当我添加静态这个词时 它是对所有狗通用的
When I don't have the word static, then it's specific to one dog.
当我没有加上静态这个词时 它就是针对某一只狗的
And if I tried to make this method on the right static, if I tried to add the word static here, which we saw from before, it's not going to work.
而且如果我试图将这个方法设置为静态 如果我试图在这里添加静态这个词 就像我们之前看到的那样 它是不会起作用的
It's going to complain and say, well, this can't be static because it's referencing a specific dog.
它会抱怨并说 嗯 这不能是静态的 因为它引用了一个特定的狗
And if the method is static, then it's thinking about all dogs.
如果这个方法是静态的 那么它考虑的是所有的狗
So that's the key difference between static and non-static.
这就是静态和非静态之间的关键区别
It's one of those things you'll get more comfortable with through practice, but that's kind of the high-level overview.
这是你通过实践会更加熟悉的事情之一 但这算是一个高层次的概述
OK, great.
好的 太好了
So what is the point of static methods in the first place?
那么静态方法的意义是什么呢
It seems like non-static methods are simply more powerful, because in non-static methods, I can use the specific weight in pounds.
看起来非静态方法更加强大 因为在非静态方法中 我可以使用磅为单位的具体重量
But in the static method, I can't use weight in pounds, because general purpose dogs, they don't have a specific weight in pounds.
但在静态方法中 我不能使用磅为单位的重量 因为通用狗 它们没有具体的磅为单位的重量
So what's the point of a static method?
静态方法有什么用呢
Well, sometimes, some classes are simply never instantiated.
嗯 有时候 有些类根本就不会被实例化
So for example, there is a class in Java called Math.
比如说 在Java中有一个叫做Math的类
And if I want to use methods in the math class, it is much nicer to say something like, the mathematics class, the blueprint for math, has a method called round.
如果我想要使用数学类中的方法 说出类似“数学类 数学的蓝图 有一个叫做round的方法”会更好
So I can say, mathematics, please round 5.6.
我可以说 数学类 请将5.6四舍五入
That makes a lot more sense than saying something like, let's create a new math, whatever that means, and then ask the specific math to round 5.6.
这比说一些像是 让我们创建一个新的数学 不知道那意味着什么 然后让特定的数学将5.6四舍五入要有意义得多
What does it mean to create a specific math?
创建一个特定的数学是什么意思呢
It makes more sense to say, let's have the general idea of mathematics round 5.6.
更合理的说法是 让我们将数学的大致概念四舍五入到5.6
So that's one reason why you might want to have static methods.
这就是你可能希望使用静态方法的一个原因
And as we'll see now, you can also have static and non-static methods in the same class.
正如我们现在将要看到的 你也可以在同一个类中同时拥有静态方法和非静态方法
So let's go into IntelliJ again, and let's write some methods that are static and non-static to really make sure we know what's going on.
那么让我们再次进入 IntelliJ 让我们编写一些静态和非静态方法 确保我们真正明白发生了什么
Okay.
好的
So here's what I'm going to do.
我要做的是
I'm going to write a method to compare two dogs, and I'm going to write it two different ways.
我将编写一个比较两只狗的方法 并且我将以两种不同的方式编写它
I'm going to write the static version, then I'm going to write the non-static version.
我要写静态版本 然后我要写非静态版本
So first, I'm going to write a static version that compares two dogs.
首先 我要写一个比较两只狗的静态版本
So this will be a static function.
这将是一个静态函数
It's general purpose to all dogs.
它适用于所有狗
So you can think of it like in the blueprint of dogs, there's a little set of instructions for how to compare two dogs.
你可以把它想象成在狗的蓝图中 有一小组指令来比较两只狗
So I'll say,
所以我会说
Dog D1, Dog D2.
狗 D1 狗 D2
So it takes in two dogs as arguments.
它接受两只狗作为参数
And I can say something like, well, if the first dog weighs more than the second dog, then I will return the first dog.
而且我可以说一些像 嗯 如果第一只狗比第二只狗重 那么我会返回第一只狗
Otherwise, I'll return the second dog.
否则 我会返回第二只狗
And this is a static method.
这是一个静态方法
And what does it mean when it's a static method?
那么当它是一个静态方法时意味着什么呢
It means when I call this method, I have to invoke it using the class name.
这意味着当我调用这个方法时 我必须使用类名来调用它
So this is not a specific dog judging dogs.
这不是一种特定的狗来评判狗
It's just kind of the idea of dogs or the blueprint of dogs comparing dogs.
这只是狗的概念或狗的蓝图在比较狗
OK, in order to do this, I'm going to need some dogs to test my maxDog function and do some experiments.
好的 为了做到这一点 我需要一些狗来测试我的maxDog函数并进行一些实验
So who would like to volunteer their dog?
那么谁愿意让他们的狗志愿参加这个实验呢
in this experiment.
在这个实验中
Yes.
是的
Please tell me your dog's name.
请告诉我你狗的名字
Chester.
切斯特
Okay.
好的
And I don't know if this is like appropriate to ask or whatever.
我也不知道这个问题合不合适问 总之
How much does your dog weigh?
你家狗狗有多重
You can make up a number if you need to.
如果需要 你可以编一个数字
17 pounds.
17 磅
Okay.
好的
Cool.
酷
Looks good.
看起来不错
I forgot the word new.
我忘了这个单词是新的
Okay.
好的
But we need a second dog.
但是我们需要第二只狗
So who else would like to volunteer their dog?
那么还有谁愿意志愿让他们的狗参加呢
All right.
好的
What's your dog's name?
你的狗叫什么名字
Yusuf.
尤素夫
Did I spell it right?
我拼对了吗
Okay, we'll go with it.
好的 我们就用这个
And how much does Yusuf weigh?
尤素夫有多重
150.
All right.
好的
He's a very large boy.
他是个很大只的男孩
Okay.
好的
Okay, great, we have two dogs.
好的 太棒了 我们有两只狗
Now I'd like to call the MaxDog function.
现在我想调用MaxDog函数
How do I call it?
我该怎么调用它
Well, the MaxDog function is static, so I'm not going to ask a specific dog to do the judging.
嗯 MaxDog函数是静态的 我不会要求特定的狗来判断
I'm going to say, the dog class, the idea of a dog, the blueprint of a dog, please call your MaxDog function, and please tell me, between Chester and Yusuf,
我会说 狗类 狗的概念 狗的蓝图 请调用你的MaxDog函数 并告诉我 在切斯特和尤素夫之间
which is the bigger dog.
哪只狗更大
Maybe I'll assign it to some variable called larger, and then I'll have the larger dog make a noise.
也许我会把它分配给一个叫做 larger 的变量 然后我会让更大的狗发出声音
OK, so I'll run this experiment.
好的 我来运行这个实验
Hopefully, if everything goes well, then we'll hear the beautiful aroo sound from the larger dog, Yusuf.
希望一切顺利的话 我们就能听到更大的狗 Yusuf 发出美妙的 aroo 声音
OK, so there's the aroo sound.
好的 这就是 aroo 声音
Does this Yusuf dog typically say aroo, or is that not something they do?
Yusuf 这只狗通常会说 aroo 吗 还是说它们不会这样做
No answer.
没有回答
OK, that's all right.
好的 没关系
OK, we'll pretend the use of dog goes aroo.
好的 我们就假装狗的使用是对的
So there we go.
我们就这样
Looks great.
看起来不错
OK, what if I wanted to write this function and this method as a non-static method, though?
好的 但是如果我想把这个函数和这个方法写成非静态方法呢
So now, instead of having this general dog blueprint that tells me how to compare dogs, what if I want to have a specific dog do the judging?
现在 不再是有一个通用的狗蓝图告诉我如何比较狗 如果我想让一个特定的狗来判断呢
So I could write public DogMaxDog.
我可以写 public DogMaxDog
And this time, the word static is gone.
而这次 static 这个词消失了
Why is it gone?
为什么它不见了
Because I don't want to have the general idea of dogs do the judging.
因为我不想让狗的概念来评判
I want a specific dog to do the judging for me.
我想要一个具体的狗来为我评判
So this is now a method that's going to be called with a specific dog in mind.
现在这是一个会被调用并指定特定狗的方法
So I'll have this dog compare itself to some other dog.
我将让这只狗与其他狗进行比较
And now I'll have to say something like, if my weight in pounds, me, and the reason why I can access my weight in pounds
现在我将不得不说一些像是 如果我的体重是以磅为单位的 我 而我可以访问我的体重的原因
is because this is a non-static method.
是因为这是一个非静态方法
It's specific to one dog, and it's not general purpose to all dogs.
这是针对一个狗的特定情况 并不适用于所有狗
So I can say, if my weight in pounds is greater than the other dog's weight in pounds, then I will return myself.
我可以说 如果我的体重以磅为单位比另一只狗的体重更重 那么我会返回自己
How do I return a reference to myself?
我怎么返回一个指向自己的引用
We'll use that special keyword in Java from last time, this.
我们将使用上次讲到的Java中的那个特殊关键字 this
Otherwise, did it work?
否则 它有效果吗
Otherwise,
否则
The other dog is larger, so I'll return the other dog.
另一只狗更大 所以我会返回另一只狗
So now the difference is I'm not having the general idea of a dog do the judging.
现在的区别是 我不是让一般的狗来判断
I'm going to make a specific dog do the judging.
我要让一只具体的狗来判断
So I'm going to take this method that was static.
我要采用这个原本是静态的方法
I'm now going to call it using non-static.
现在我要用非静态的方式来调用它
So I hope, is Chester like a really smart dog?
那么 切斯特像是一只非常聪明的狗吗
Is it like one of the dumber dogs out there?
它是不是属于那些比较笨的狗之一
Brilliant dog.
聪明的狗
Okay.
好的
Well, Chester now has a new trick, which is Chester knows how to compare itself to other dogs.
嗯 切斯特现在有了一个新技能 就是切斯特知道如何与其他狗进行比较
What an amazing trick.
多么了不起的技能啊
So we're going to say Chester.maxDog.
所以我们要说切斯特.maxDog
The difference now is I'm using a specific dog to do the judging, and it's going to compare itself to Yusuf.
现在的区别是我正在使用一个具体的狗来进行评判 它将与尤素夫进行比较
And Yusuf will probably just like sit on the dog or something, but it'd be larger.
尤素夫可能只会坐在狗上或者做些什么 但它会更大一些
And what will probably happen is the larger dog will make noise again.
而且很可能会发生的是更大的狗会再次制造噪音
So we get a roo again.
我们又得到了一只袋鼠
And the main difference is that now I called MaxDog using the non-static version of MaxDog.
而主要的区别是现在我使用非静态版本的 MaxDog 调用了 MaxDog
So which one is correct?
那么哪个是正确的
Which one is better?
哪一个更好呢
Well, it's kind of a matter of your own dog-related preferences.
嗯 这有点取决于你自己与狗相关的偏好
So do you like the idea of dogs comparing themselves to other dogs, like we did here?
那么你喜欢狗之间相互比较的想法吗 就像我们在这里做的一样
Do you think it's appropriate for a dog to compare itself to other dogs?
你认为狗应该把自己和其他狗比较吗
Or do you think it's better to have an impartial observer, the static method, take in two dogs, and then I'm back, and then tell me which one is larger?
或者你认为让一个客观的观察者——静态方法——接收两只狗 然后再回来告诉我哪只更大更好
OK, I'm loud again.
好吧 我又大声了
Apparently, also not using this means that they can't hear you.
显然 也不使用这个意味着他们听不到你
Aw, aw, what happened?
哎呀 哎呀 发生了什么
OK.
好的
Are we back?
我们回来了吗
We knack.
我们回来了
Let's go.
走吧
OK.
好的
All right.
So as we were saying, which one you prefer is up to your preference.
就像我们说的那样 你更喜欢哪一个取决于你的偏好
So do you like having an impartial observer, or do you like having specific dogs do tricks and compare themselves to other dogs?
你喜欢有一个公正的观察者 还是喜欢特定的狗做把戏并将自己与其他狗比较
Which one you like is kind of up to you.
你喜欢哪一个取决于你
So here we have the static version.
这里我们有静态版本
You saw earlier the non-static version.
你之前看到了非静态版本
One final thing I will note is that here we saw there are instance variables, but you can also have static variables.
最后要注意的一点是 这里我们看到有实例变量 但你也可以有静态变量
So I realize we're sort of hitting the limit of the amount of things you can fit in your brain at once.
我意识到我们有点触及了你一次能装进脑子里的东西的极限
So I'll just briefly mention that if you want to, you can also have static variables.
我只是简单提一下 如果你想的话 你也可以有静态变量
And these would be variables that are general to the entire dog class.
这些将是整个 dog 类通用的变量
So for example, all dogs have the same scientific name.
例如 所有的狗都有相同的学名
So there it is.
就是这样了
I think I spelled it right.
我想我拼对了
So this is the scientific name of all dogs.
这就是所有狗的学名
It's not a scientific name of one specific dog.
这不是某一特定狗的学名
It's of all dogs.
这是所有狗的学名
So now, in the dog launcher class, I could ask a question like, well, how do I use this?
现在 在狗发射器类中 我可以问一个问题 比如 我怎么使用这个
I shouldn't ask a specific dog what its scientific name is.
我不应该问某只特定的狗它的学名是什么
I could just ask a question like, please tell me what is the scientific name of all dogs?
我可以直接问一个问题 比如 请告诉我所有狗的学名是什么
And when I do that and I run it, it should tell me that all dogs have the scientific name Canis familiaris.
当我这样做并运行它时 它应该告诉我所有的狗的科学名称是犬科犬
There it is.
就是这样
So if I want to use a static variable, I can do so.
如果我想使用一个静态变量 我可以这样做
But that would be something that is general to the whole class and not a scientific or not a variable, not a scientific name that is specific to one dog.
但那将是整个类通用的东西 而不是一个变量 不是一个特定于一只狗的科学名称
So it's a constant for every dog that I ever create.
对于我创建的每一只狗 它都是一个常数
They will all have the same scientific name.
它们都会有相同的科学名称
OK, there's some more reading about it if you like.
好的 如果你喜欢的话 这里有更多关于它的阅读
And there's the methods that we saw from earlier.
然后是我们之前看过的方法
OK, questions.
好的 有问题吗
I know it's a lot to fit in your brain at once before I move on.
我知道一下子要记住这么多东西确实有点难 但在我继续之前 请确保你跟上了
Everyone good?
大家都准备好了吗
OK.
好的
Oh, one more?
还有一个问题吗
I'll take one.
我来解答一个
Sorry, can you say that, but louder?
抱歉 你能再说一遍 但声音大点吗
So the question was, when I mixed up the methods, this is a method that is static, and then this is the method that is non-static.
问题是 当我混淆了这些方法时 这是一个静态的方法 然后这是一个非静态的方法
I don't know if that helps.
我不知道这是否有帮助
So I wrote two methods, one was static, one was non-static.
我写了两个方法 一个是静态的 一个是非静态的
Classes can have both.
类可以同时拥有两者
Okay, perfect.
好的 完美
Anything else?
还有其他吗
Oh shoot, that's a lot of hands.
哦糟糕 那有好多人手
Okay, I'll take a couple, then I have to keep it going because of all the tech stuff that slowed us down.
好吧 我会拿几个 然后因为所有的技术东西拖慢了我们的速度 我必须继续前进
Okay, question?
好的 问题
Oh, if I put Chester.
哦 如果我放了切斯特
So I think Java is OK with this, but I would argue it's kind of bad style, even Java's complaining and saying, hey, that's kind of ugly.
我认为Java可以处理这个 但我会认为这样做有点不好 甚至Java也在抱怨说 嘿 这有点丑陋
So it's probably better to say, what is the scientific name of all dogs?
最好是说 所有狗的学名是什么
But I guess if you wanted to ask for a specific dog's scientific name, it works out, though it's a little bit ugly.
但我猜如果你想问一个具体的狗的学名 它也可以 尽管有点丑陋
Great question, though.
很好的问题 不过
OK, I'll take one more, then I've got to keep it going.
好的 我再回答一个 然后我得继续下去了
Yeah, there was a great question, which is, how did I access both even though they were called the same thing?
是的 有一个很好的问题 就是 即使它们被称为同一个东西 我如何访问它们
We'll talk about this a little bit more later in the class.
我们稍后在课上会再谈这个
But what happened was I overloaded the method, and Java looked at the number of arguments to figure out which one to call.
但发生的是我重载了这个方法 Java看了参数的数量来确定调用哪个
That's the short answer.
这就是简短的回答
OK, great questions.
好的 很棒的问题
I'm sure there are more great questions, but I'll keep it going, and I'll come back later if I have time.
我确定还有更多很棒的问题 但我会继续 如果有时间的话 我会稍后回来的
OK, there's a practice question, but you lucked out because we don't have time for it.
好的 有一个练习问题 但你运气好 因为我们没时间做它
If you would like to, there's a video of it.
如果你愿意 有一个视频可以看
So I encourage you to check it out if all of this is feeling a little bit shaky.
我鼓励你查看一下 如果这一切感觉有点摇摆不定
All right, here comes the second part of today.
好的 今天的第二部分来了
So the reason why today is so chaotic is because I also had to set this up from scratch.
今天之所以这么混乱 是因为我还得从零开始设置这个
It's kind of new, so there might be some kinks in the whole thing.
这有点新 所以整个事情可能有些小问题
But hopefully, it's helpful, so we'll see how it goes.
但愿有帮助 我们就看看效果如何
OK, so, so far from CSXDNA or CS88 or Data8, when something doesn't work, how do you debug it?
好的 那么 到目前为止从 CSXDNA 或 CS88 或 Data8 来看 当某事不起作用时 你怎么调试它呢
What are our strategies?
我们的策略是什么
Well, besides asking a staff member right away, what are our strategies for debugging?
嗯 除了立即询问工作人员之外 我们调试的策略是什么
Yeah, we wrote our pseudocode.
是的 我们编写了伪代码
That's a great one.
那真是太棒了
What if you already have the code written, and if something's wrong, it doesn't do what you expect?
如果你已经编写了代码 但出了问题 它不按预期运行怎么办
Any ideas?
有什么想法吗
Python visualizer.
Python 可视化工具
Yeah, Python visualizer is a good one.
是的 Python 可视化工具是一个不错的选择
Has anyone ever just shoved a bunch of print statements inside?
有没有人曾经把一堆打印语句塞进去过
So those are the kind of things that we've done.
这些就是我们做过的事情
But today, I'm going to show you a brand new tool, which is going to allow you to interactively debug programs.
但是今天 我要向你展示一个全新的工具 它将允许你交互式地调试程序
It's really cool.
这真的很酷
I love it.
我喜欢它
It saved my life in this class.
在这门课上 它救了我的命
And hopefully, it does so for you as well.
希望对你也有同样的帮助
OK.
好的
So, so far, you might have been using print statements.
到目前为止 你可能一直在使用打印语句
You might have just stared at the code really hard and hoped that the bug came to you.
你可能只是盯着代码看 希望错误会出现在你面前
But in 61B, the programs are larger, and it's not going to be possible to just stare at a piece of code and have the bug come to you.
但在61B中 程序更庞大 仅仅盯着一段代码是找不到错误的
So instead, we're going to use the debugging tool inside IntelliJ.
我们不用这个 而是要在IntelliJ里使用调试工具
It's really powerful.
它真的很强大
It's got tons of features, some of which I don't even know about.
它有很多功能 有些我甚至不知道
And we'll use it to try and find the bugs in our code.
我们会用它来找代码中的错误
So to do that, I have to have some code to debug.
为了做到这一点 我必须有一些要调试的代码
So let's write some code to debug, and then let's use the debugger to fix it.
那么让我们写一些需要调试的代码 然后使用调试器来修复它
Everyone's like whispering, did I do something wrong again?
每个人都在窃窃私语 是不是我又做错了什么
OK, let me know if I did.
好的 如果我做错了 请告诉我
All right, so here's the method I'm going to try and debug.
好的 这是我要尝试调试的方法
It's called larger than four neighbors.
这个方法叫做大于四个邻居
And what's going to happen here is I'm going to take in an array of dogs.
这里要发生的是 我将接收一个狗的数组
And it's going to return every dog that is bigger than the two dogs to its left and the two dogs to its right.
它将返回比左边两只狗和右边两只狗都大的每一只狗
So for example, here's my array of dogs.
所以 举个例子 这是我的一组狗
This dog of size 30, it is greater than the two dogs to its left and the two dogs to its right.
这只大小为30的狗 它比左边两只狗和右边两只狗都大
This dog 40, it is greater than the two dogs to its left and the two dogs to its right.
这只狗40 比它左右两只狗都大
If there isn't a dog, we can ignore it.
如果没有狗 我们可以忽略它
But this 20 would not be returned, because it is not greater than all of the dogs to its left and right.
但是这20不会被返回 因为它不比左右所有的狗都大
There's a dog to its right that is a little bit larger.
右边有一只狗比它大一点
So that's the function we're going to try to write and debug together.
这就是我们要一起编写和调试的函数
OK, you're all staring at me funny.
好的 你们都用奇怪的眼神看着我
Let's make sure you understand this function and what it does.
让我们确保你们理解这个函数及其作用
So here's another array of dogs.
这是另一个狗数组
Tell me, and try and ponder or think about what the answer is, which dogs get returned if I call larger than four neighbors on this particular array?
告诉我 并试着考虑或思考答案是什么 如果我对这个特定的数组调用大于四个邻居 哪些狗会被返回
So remember, the way I check is, this dog of size 20, is it greater than both of its neighbors on the left and both of its neighbors on the right?
记住 我检查的方式是 这只大小为20的狗 它是否比左右两边的邻居都要大
Yes, so I should return the 20.
是的 所以我应该返回这个20
This 10 is not greater than all of its neighbors to the left and right, so I don't return it.
这个10不比左右两边的所有邻居都要大 所以我不返回它
This 22 is greater than all the dogs to its left and the right, so I'll return the 22.
这个22比它左右的所有狗都要大 所以我会返回这个22
So hopefully we're all clear that these are the dogs that should be returned.
希望大家都清楚 这些是应该被返回的狗
OK, let's go write some code.
好的 让我们去写一些代码吧
So I'm going to fast forward in this demo a little bit, and let's pretend somebody else has come by.
我会在这个演示中快进一下 假装有人来了
Oh, it's Josh Hugg, the person who used to teach this class.
哦 是Josh Hugg 以前教这门课的人
He's come by and given me this wonderful code that he's written.
他过来给我这个他写的很棒的代码
He called it Beautiful Solution because it's so beautiful.
他把它称为“美丽的解决方案” 因为它太美了
OK.
好的
So I'll uncomment it out.
我会把它注释掉
Here's my beautiful larger-than-four-neighbors solution all written out for me.
这是我漂亮的大于四个邻居的解决方案 所有内容都写好了
Let's see if it works. So here's the array from before.
我们来看看它是否有效  这是之前的数组
It's the same one that you just saw in the slides.
就是你刚刚在幻灯片中看到的那个
And remember that the two dogs that are greater than all of its neighbors to the left and right are 20 and 22.
记住 左右邻居都比它小的两个狗的年龄分别是20和22
So beautiful solution.
真是漂亮的解决方案
Activate.
激活
Show me the 20 and the 22. Okay.
给我看看20和22
Well, that isn't so good.
嗯 这不太好
I don't see the 20 and the 22.
我没看到20和22
So this code is broken, and we have to fix it together.
这段代码有问题 我们得一起修复一下
So let's try and use the debugger and try and dive in and see what's going on.
那我们试着使用调试器 深入看看到底出了什么问题
Why is this code broken?
为什么这段代码出问题了
Let's try and figure it out.
咱们试着搞清楚一下
Okay, so how do I do that?
好的 那我怎么做呢
Well, the first thing I'm going to do is I'm going to recognize that so far I've been pressing this play button.
嗯 我要做的第一件事是要意识到到目前为止我一直在按这个播放按钮
I know it's kind of small, but the play button is how I run programs in IntelliJ.
我知道它有点小 但在IntelliJ中 播放按钮是我运行程序的方式
However, if I wanted to debug a program, then I can use this debug button.
然而 如果我想调试一个程序 那么我可以使用这个调试按钮
And that's going to launch the magical debugger.
那就会启动神奇的调试器
And maybe if I click the magical debugger button, it'll just give me the right answer and solve all my problems for me.
也许如果我点击这个神奇的调试器按钮 它会给我正确的答案 解决我所有的问题
Debug, activate.
调试 激活
It's OK.
没问题
Still didn't print anything.
还是没有打印任何东西
So it looks like we still have some problems.
看起来我们还是有些问题
OK, so how do I actually use the debugger?
好的 那我实际上怎么使用调试器呢
Well, the great thing about the debugger is it's going to let me pause the program at any point in time that I want.
嗯 调试器的好处在于它让我可以在任何我想要的时候暂停程序
So if I'm running this program, and normally what I would do maybe is I'd shove in some print statements to see what it's doing.
如果我正在运行这个程序 通常我可能会插入一些打印语句来查看它在做什么
But instead, I can actually force the program to pause somewhere, and then I can inspect what's going on inside the program.
但相反 我实际上可以强制程序在某个地方暂停 然后我可以检查程序内部发生了什么
It's really cool.
这真的很酷
So the way that I'm going to tell IntelliJ where to pause the program is I'm going to set something called a breakpoint.
我告诉IntelliJ暂停程序的方式是我要设置一个叫做断点的东西
I'm going to start throwing some vocabulary at you.
我要向你介绍一些词汇
You don't have to memorize it.
你不必记住它
It's simply how we talk about these things together.
这只是我们在一起讨论这些事情的方式
But I'm going to identify a line of code where I want the program to stop.
但我会确定一行代码 我希望程序停下来
So where should I set it?
那么我应该把它设置在哪里呢
Well, There's no right answer to this.
嗯  这个没有确切的答案
Debugging is kind of more like an art than a science.
调试更像是一门艺术而不是科学
So there's not necessarily a right answer.
所以并不一定有正确的答案
It's kind of like exploring to see what's going on, what's wrong with your code.
这有点像是探索去看看发生了什么 你的代码出了什么问题
So since I have no clue where to set this breakpoint, I have no idea where I want to pause the code.
既然我完全不知道应该在哪里设置断点 我也不知道想要暂停代码的地方在哪里
I don't know where the code is broken.
我不知道代码哪里出了问题
There's so many different methods.
有很多不同的方法
I'm just going to set the breakpoint at the start of the program.
我只是打算在程序的开头设置断点
That's always a good place to start. But you don't have to.
那总是一个好的开始  但你不一定要这样做
If you're doing this yourself, you could set it somewhere else.
如果你自己做这个 你可以把它设置在其他地方
So I'm going to set the breakpoint at the very start.
我打算在程序的最开始设置断点
How do I do it?
我怎么做
I click right next to the line.
我点击了行旁边
Number.
数字
So here I go.
我开始了
Okay.
好的
Breakpoint created.
创建了断点
Amazing.
太神奇了
The sound effects are not optional.
音效是必须的
You have to do it at home too.
你也得在家里做
Okay.
好的
Great.
太棒了
So now when I set the breakpoint, what's going to happen is when I run the program, it's going to start executing, and then it's going to pause at this point for me to inspect what's going on inside.
现在当我设置断点时 会发生的是当我运行程序时 它会开始执行 然后会在这一点暂停 让我检查里面发生了什么
So I'm going to click the debug button again.
我要再次点击调试按钮
It's going to build.
它会构建
And then, whoosh. OK, there it is.
然后 哗啦一声  好的 就是这样
And it stopped at the first line.
然后它停在第一行
Amazing.
太神奇了
OK.
好的
So now what's happened is the program is paused at this line in blue.
现在发生的是程序暂停在这一行 用蓝色标出来
It has not executed that line yet.
它还没有执行这一行
But now the program is paused, and I can start exploring what's going on in the program.
但是现在程序被暂停了 我可以开始探索程序里发生了什么了
Pretty cool.
挺酷的
But I'm at the very start of the program, so nothing interesting has happened yet.
但我现在在程序的最开始阶段 所以还没发生什么有趣的事情
So I want to go to the next line.
我想要跳到下一行
How do I go to the next line?
我怎么跳到下一行呢
Well, maybe I should set another breakpoint and start over.
也许我应该设置另一个断点 重新开始
But in fact, the debugger has a button to let me step to the next line of code, so I can execute the code line by line and see what's going on.
但实际上 调试器有一个按钮可以让我跳到代码的下一行 所以我可以逐行执行代码 看看发生了什么
So how do I do that?
那我该怎么做呢
There's a little button.
有一个小按钮
It says Step Over.
上面写着Step Over
I'm going to click on it, and it's going to take me to the next line.
我要点击它 然后它会带我到下一行
So here I go.
我现在要做的就是
I click on it.
我点击它
Next line of code.
下一行代码
Okay, amazing.
好的 太棒了
So what happened when I executed this line of code?
那么当我执行这行代码时发生了什么
It split across a couple lines, but what happened was, I know it's kind of small, I don't know how to make it bigger, but it created the brand new array of dogs.
它分成了几行 但发生的事情是 我知道它有点小 我不知道怎么让它变大 但它创建了全新的狗数组
And if I look in the debugger, what's really cool is that the debugger is going to show me the status of all the variables.
如果我在调试器中查看 很酷的是调试器会显示给我所有变量的状态
as I run through this program line by line.
当我逐行运行这个程序时
So this array of dogs that I just created, it's right there.
我刚刚创建的这个狗数组 就在那里
Look, there's the array of dogs.
看 那就是狗数组
And if I open them up, I can see, well, the dog at index 0 has weight 10, just like I expected.
如果我打开它们 我可以看到 索引0处的狗的重量是10 正如我所预期的
The dog at weight 1 has, or index 1, has size 15.
索引1处的狗 其大小是15
Then the next one is 20.
然后下一个是20
So the dogs that I created, they're now here in the debugging console.
我创建的这些狗 现在都在调试控制台里
And it tells me the status of all the variables.
它显示了所有变量的状态
Pretty cool.
挺酷的
Okay, you all don't seem very impressed, so I'm going to have to pull out some more tricks.
好吧 你们似乎不太印象深刻 所以我得拿出更多的招数了
All right, so here we go.
好的 那我们开始吧
I'm going to keep stepping, so I'm going to call this larger than four neighbor dogs, so it's going to get assigned to big dogs one, so I'm going to step and then... Okay, I created the big dogs one, but wait a minute.
我要继续执行 我要称呼这些大于四个邻居的狗 它将被分配到大狗一 我要继续执行然后... 好的 我创建了大狗一 但等一下
It's kind of small, hard to see, I don't know how to make it bigger, but what it says is big dogs one length equals zero.
有点小 看不太清楚 我不知道怎么让它变大 但它说大狗一的长度等于零
Huh, it seems like I was supposed to get two dogs, remember you're supposed to get the dog 20 and the dog 22, but when I called larger than four neighbors, big dogs one came out with length zero.
哎呀 好像我应该得到两只狗 记得你应该得到狗20和狗22 但当我调用大于四个邻居时 大狗一的长度为零
Problem, we found it.
问题找到了
So the problem is somewhere in this larger-than-four-neighbors code.
问题应该在这个大于四个邻居的代码中的某处
So we need to dive inside this code and see what's going on.
我们需要深入这段代码并看看发生了什么
So how do we do that?
那么我们怎么做呢
Well, one annoying thing about the debugger is that you cannot step backwards.
嗯 关于调试器的一个让人烦恼的事情是你不能向后步进
I wish you could, but the debugger is not smart enough to do that.
我希望你能 但调试器还不够智能
So I'll just start the debugger over again.
我只能重新启动调试器
So I'll rerun it from scratch.
我会从头再运行一遍
It starts again at the breakpoint that I set.
它会从我设置的断点重新开始
I step over.
我跨过去
And now I'm at this line, where I'm calling larger than four neighbors.
现在我在这一行 我在调用大于四个邻居
But I don't want to just step over this and keep going, because I know the problem lives in larger than four neighbors.
但我不想跳过这个继续 因为我知道问题出在大于四个邻居
That's where it's broken.
那就是它的破绽所在
It was supposed to return two dogs, but it returned zero.
它应该返回两只狗 但它返回了零
So now it's time to dive inside this method and see what's going on.
现在是时候深入到这个方法里看看到底发生了什么
So how do I do that?
那我该怎么做呢
Well, there's a button called Step Into.
嗯 有一个叫做Step Into的按钮
And the contrast between Step Over and Step Into is, when I called Step Over, when I pushed that button, what happened?
Step Over和Step Into之间的对比是 当我调用Step Over时 当我按下那个按钮时 发生了什么
I went to the next line.
我跳到了下一行
And I skipped over this function.
而且我跳过了这个函数
And Java executed that function without showing me what's going on.
而Java执行了那个函数 而不显示发生了什么
But I know the problems in there.
但我知道里面的问题
I want to go inside.
我想要进去看看
So when I call Step Into, I'm going to dive into this function.
当我调用Step Into时 我会进入这个函数内部
And I get to see what's going on.
我可以看到发生了什么
So I step into.
我走进去
And now I'm inside the LargerThanFourNeighbors function.
现在我在 LargerThanFourNeighbors 函数里面
Ooh, ah, OK.
哦 啊 好的
So now I'm in here, and I get to see what's going on.
现在我在这里 我可以看到发生了什么
So I'm going to start stepping through this line by line.
我要逐行开始浏览这段代码
It's OK if you haven't seen this code before, because I am showing it to you for the first time.
如果你以前没有看过这段代码 没关系 因为我第一次给你展示
So as we go through, we have to puzzle through, what is this code doing?
当我们进行时 我们必须去迷惑 这段代码在做什么
What do I expect the code to do?
我期待代码会做什么
What is the code actually doing?
这段代码实际上在做什么
And how do I know what the code is actually doing?
我怎么知道代码实际上在做什么
Well, I can use the same strategy of stepping through this code line by line by line.
嗯 我可以使用相同的策略一行一行地逐步执行这段代码
So here I am at the start.
我现在在这里开始
My dogs array is still here.
我的 dogs 数组仍然在这里
So my 11 dogs, they're all still here with all their weight in pounds sitting there waiting for me to compare them.
我的11只狗 它们都还在这里 它们的体重都是以磅为单位的 坐在那里等着我来比较它们
Great.
太好了
So I step over.
我跨过去
I create a return dogs array.
我创建一个返回狗的数组
It's totally empty.
它完全是空的
OK.
好的
Can I initialize an integer count to zero?
我可以初始化一个整数计数为零吗
And look, it's right there, count equals zero.
看 就在那儿 计数等于零
And as I step through this code, count is going to get updated based on what the code is doing.
当我逐步执行这段代码时 计数将根据代码的操作进行更新
So this is going to let me, it's as if I had written print count everywhere in the code.
这会让我 就好像我在代码的每个地方都写了print count一样
It lets me see what's going on with count as I step through this code one by one.
它让我能够逐步查看代码执行过程中计数的变化
Great.
太好了
Now I've made it to the for loop.
现在我已经进入了for循环
For loop syntax in Java is a little bit funny, but there it is.
在Java中 for循环的语法有点有趣 但就是这样
What this is saying is I want to iterate from i equals 0 all the way up to dogs.length, which is the length of the array, and I'm going to add one every single time.
这是在说 我要从 i 等于 0 开始迭代直到 dogs.length 也就是数组的长度 每次都要加一
So here I go.
所以 我开始了
I step over, and now what do I have?
我跨过去 现在我有什么
I have i equals 0.
我有 i 等于 0
Great.
太棒了
That tells me that in this for loop, I'm currently on the 0th iteration, where i is equal to 0.
这告诉我 在这个 for 循环中 我当前正在第 0 次迭代 其中 i 等于 0
OK. Now what's happening?
好的  现在发生了什么
Well, It seems like I'm calling this function isBiggestOf4, which Josh Hugg wrote for me many years ago.
嗯  看起来我在调用这个函数 isBiggestOf4 Josh Hugg 多年前为我编写的
And this function is supposed to return true if that dog is larger than its four neighbors.
而这个函数应该在那只狗比它的四个邻居大时返回 true
OK, great.
好的 太好了
So this function should return true if the zeroth dog is greater than its four neighbors.
这个函数应该在零号狗比它的四个邻居大时返回 true
So I come back up here, and if I'm curious, well, what are the dogs?
我回到这里 如果我好奇 那么 这些狗是什么
Well, they're in my debugger.
嗯 它们在我的调试器里
The 0th dog has weight 10, its neighbors are 15 and 20, so is big as the 4.
第 0 只狗的重量为 10 它的邻居是 15 和 20 和第 4 只狗一样大
So I think, I'm like, what should this thing return?
我想 我就像 这个东西应该返回什么
Should it be true?
应该是 true 吗
Should it be false?
应该是 false 吗
What do we think?
我们觉得呢
Is big as the 4.
和第 4 只狗一样大
Is this supposed to be true on the 0th dog?
这应该在第0只狗上是真的吗
False, hence for false?
假的 所以为了假吗
Okay, wow, we have hands for false.
好的 哇 我们为假有处理
So I think it's supposed to be false.
我认为它应该是假的
Okay, so let's see what happens.
好的 让我们看看会发生什么
Well, when I step over it, if it's true, then I'm going to be at this line.
嗯 当我跨过它时 如果它是真的 那么我会在这一行
If it's false, I'm going to skip back to the for loop.
如果它是假的 我会跳回到for循环
So let's see what happens.
那我们来看看会发生什么
The suspense.
悬念
So I click step over, and it teleports me back to the for loop.
我点击step over 它就把我传送回for循环了
Why is that?
为什么呢
Because the condition was false.
因为条件是假的
These two lines of code did not execute.
这两行代码没有执行
That's good.
那就好
That's what we expected.
这正是我们期待的
Let's do it again.
让我们再做一次
That was so much fun that I want to do it one more time.
那真的太有趣了 我想再做一次
So now I'm going to do it when i is equal to 1.
现在当 i 等于 1 时 我就要这样做
How do I know that i is equal to 1?
我怎么知道 i 是否等于 1 呢
Well, if I look inside the debugger, it tells me i is equal to 1.
嗯 如果我在调试器里看一下 它告诉我 i 等于 1
That tells me where I am in the debugging process.
这告诉我我在调试过程中的位置
And again, I'm going to call isBiggestOf4 on the same dogs array and i equals 1.
再次 我要在相同的 dogs 数组上调用 isBiggestOf4 而 i 等于 1
And this is going to tell me, the first dog of size 15, are you greater than all of your neighbors?
这会告诉我 尺寸为 15 的第一只狗 你比你所有邻居都大吗
Well, there's 15 right there, but then its neighbor is 20.
好吧 这里有 15 但它的邻居是 20
That's larger.
那更大
So this dog is not the biggest of its neighbors.
这只狗不是它的邻居中最大的
So when I step over, I should expect to see false.
当我跨过去时 我应该期待看到 false
I step over, it skips over those two lines.
我跨过去 它会跳过这两行
Okay, everything is working as expected so far.
好的 到目前为止一切都按预期进行
Sometimes debugging gets a little bit tedious like this, but I promise you exciting things are about to happen, because now I'm looking at i equals 2.
有时候调试会变得有点乏味 但我向你保证 精彩的事情即将发生 因为现在我正在看 i 等于 2
So I step,
我迈出了一步
i is now equal to 2.
i 现在等于 2
And I want to know, dog number 2, the one with size 20, are you larger than both of your neighbors to the left and right?
我想知道 狗狗编号为 2 尺寸为 20 的狗狗 你比左右两边的邻居都大吗
Well, this 20 is greater than 15 and 10.
好吧 这个 20 大于 15 和 10
It's also greater than 15 and 10.
它也大于 15 和 10
So this dog, which it is biggest the former turn this time?
这只狗 它是前一个转弯时最大的吗
Hopefully true.
希望是真的
So when I step over, am I going to get true?
那我一踏过去 是不是就会变成真的
I step over.
我踏过去
If it's true, I should start executing the stuff inside the if statement.
如果是真的 我应该开始执行if语句里面的东西
I step over.
我踏过去
Oh, it's false.
哦 这是假的
Interesting.
有趣
So that tells me that when I called isBiggestOfFour on dog number two, it should have given me true, but it gave me false.
这告诉我 当我在狗编号为二的时候调用 isBiggestOfFour 应该返回 true 但它却返回了 false
That's a difference between expectation and reality.
这就是期望和现实之间的差异
That's how I know something has gone wrong.
这就是我知道出了什么问题的方式
So now I want to go back and see what was the problem with isBiggestOfFour.
现在我想回去看看 isBiggestOfFour 函数有什么问题
So I'm going to have to start over because I can't go backwards in the debugger.
我得重新开始 因为在调试器中我不能倒退
A little bit annoying, but what can you do?
有点烦人 但能怎么办呢
Okay, I'll show you a couple tricks though.
好的 我会给你看几个小技巧的
So one thing I can do is like, I know where the problem is now.
我能做的一件事就是 我知道问题出在哪里了
The problem is right here on this line, and I was calling isBiggest to four.
问题就在这一行 而且我一直在调用isBiggest到四
So I'm not going to waste my time stepping over and over again.
我不会浪费时间一遍又一遍地单步执行了
I'm just going to say this breakpoint, I'm going to send it away.
我只会说一声断点 然后让它消失
So I'm going to click it again.
我再点击一次
It's gone into wherever.
它就进入了某个地方
And then I'm going to set another breakpoint here.
然后我要在这里设置另一个断点
So now the program is going to pause here for me.
现在程序会在这里为我暂停
It's going to run all the way to this line and pause here.
它会一直运行到这一行然后在这里暂停
That's a little bit nicer, because now I don't have to step all the way through the stuff that I know is fine or not totally relevant.
这样会好一点 因为现在我不必完全逐步执行我知道没问题或者不太相关的东西
So I debug.
我调试
It teleports me to this line of code.
它会将我传送到这行代码
But right now, i is equal to 0.
但是现在 i 等于 0
But I wanted to see it when i is equal to 2.
但是我想在 i 等于 2 时看它
So I need to step a bunch more.
我需要再多按几步
So there are a couple of things I could do.
有几件事情我可以做
I could start mashing the step button. I could step, step, step, step, step.
我可以开始疯狂地按步进按钮  我可以一步一步地进行步进
Or another quicker approach is there's this little button.
另一种更快的方法是有一个小按钮
It looks like a play button, and it says resume program.
它看起来像一个播放按钮 并且上面写着恢复程序
What that does is it's going to run this program until it hits the next breakpoint.
它的作用是运行此程序 直到它达到下一个断点
Kind of cool.
挺酷的
So if I call resume, it's going to start here, it's going to execute every line of code, even if there are thousands of lines of code, and stop at the next line of code that you've highlighted to be a breakpoint.
如果我调用继续 它会从这里开始执行每一行代码 即使有成千上万行代码 也会在你标记为断点的下一行代码停下来
So I hit resume, and it teleports me back to the only breakpoint that I have, but this time, it's kind of small, but if you squint, i is equal to 1 now.
我点击继续 它会将我传送回我唯一的断点 但这次 它有点小 但如果你眯起眼睛 现在 i 等于 1
Ooh.
哦
And then if I continue the program again, it's going to run, run all the way until it hits this point again.
然后如果我再次继续执行程序 它会一直运行 一直运行直到再次达到这个点
And now i is equal to 2.
现在 i 等于 2
And I don't want to get too happy and start mashing this button, because I remember when i is equal to 2, that's when stuff started to go off the rails and things are wrong.
我也不想太高兴就开始狂按这个按钮 因为我记得当 i 等于 2 时 事情开始变得不对劲了
OK.
好的
One more little feature that I'll show you, since I have a little bit of time and you're still here.
我还有一个小功能要向你展示 因为我有点时间 而且你还在这里
One thing I really like is that if you ever want to know what's going on in the code, but the thing you want is not in the code, there's also this little box here where you can type lines of code, and it will tell you what the lines of code evaluate to right now.
有一件事我真的很喜欢 如果你想知道代码在做什么 但你想要的东西不在代码里 这里也有一个小框 你可以输入代码行 它会告诉你这些代码行现在的评估结果
This is really cool.
这真的很酷
So what if I'm not sure if isBiggestOfFour is true or false right now?
那如果我现在不确定 isBiggestOfFour 是 true 还是 false 呢
How could I ask Java whether isBiggestOfFour is true or false?
我该如何问 Java isBiggestOfFour 现在是 true 还是 false
Well, I could add a print statement.
嗯 我可以加一个打印语句
I could go in here and be like, well, I'm just going to print out is biggest of four.
我可以进入这里 就像 我只是打印出四个中最大的是哪个
I could do that and then look at the print statements and rerun the program.
我可以这样做 然后查看打印语句 重新运行程序
Or I could go into this box and I could type is biggest of four dogs.
或者我可以进入这个框 我可以键入四只狗中最大的是哪个
I'm curious about dog at position number two.
我对位于第二位置的狗很好奇
So I type two.
我输入二
And if you're ready, I hit Enter.
如果你准备好了 我按回车键
And oh my god, it came out false.
哦 我的天 它返回了false
And that tells me that is biggest of four returns false.
这告诉我 这是四个返回中最大的一个是false
Pretty cool.
相当酷
So if you ever want to, you can also type lines of code in here, and it will tell you, like, I'm actually kind of curious about dog.
所以 如果你想的话 你也可以在这里输入代码行 它会告诉你 就像 我对狗其实有点好奇
Hang on, it's 1.56.
等等 是1.56
I have four more minutes.
我还有四分钟
Okay.
好的
So I can say, what about dog number 10?
我可以说 第十只狗怎么样
And I can enter, and it tells me dog number 10 is also false, and dog number 5 is also false.
我可以输入 它告诉我第十只狗也是假的 第五只狗也是假的
So if you're ever curious about running lines of code, you can do so in here.
如果你对运行代码感兴趣 你可以在这里这样做
Okay.
好的
Guys, you haven't seen the bug yet, and you're all so eager to go.
伙计们 你们还没有看到错误 你们都急着走
You've got to see where the bug is first.
你们必须先看到错误在哪里
So we know that it is biggest of four.
我们知道它是四个中最大的
So let's go inside, and I have three minutes to find the bug.
那我们进去吧 我有三分钟时间找到 Bug
So let's do it together.
那我们一起做吧
I'm in here.
我在这里
I step isBiggest is equal to true.
我步进 isBiggest 等于 true
And we know that isBiggest should always be equal to true, because this dog is greater than both of its neighbors.
我们知道 isBiggest 应该始终等于 true 因为这只狗比它的两个邻居都大
So I start here, j is equal to negative 2.
我从这里开始 j 等于负 2
And yes, I know debugging is a little bit tedious, but we can watch it go through.
是的 我知道调试有点烦人 但我们可以看着它执行
OK, great.
好的 太棒了
So I'll skip a couple steps, since you're all so antsy.
那我会跳过几步 因为你们都这么着急
So I go through.
我继续
Now it's looking at the dog of size 15.
现在它正在查看大小为15的狗
And how do I know?
我怎么知道呢
Because the debugger is showing it to me.
因为调试器正在向我展示
And so I keep going.
我继续前进
OK, is biggest is still equal to true.
好的 最大值是否仍然等于真
How do I know?
我怎么知道
Because it's right there.
因为它就在那里
OK, then I come over.
好的 那我过来
And maybe you already see what's about to happen.
也许你已经看到接下来会发生什么
OK, so now I look.
好的 现在我看一看
And now I'm comparing the dog of size 20 against the dog of size 20.
现在我正在比较大小为20的狗和大小为20的狗
And I step.
然后我踏出一步
And I ask, is the dog of size 20 greater than or equal to the dog of size 20?
然后我问 大小为20的狗是否大于或等于大小为20的狗
Yes.
是的
And that means that when I step into the next line of code, isBiggest is going to be set to false.
那意味着当我进入下一行代码时 isBiggest将被设置为false
I don't want that.
我不想要那样
So this is where expectation and reality diverge, and this is where my problem is.
这就是期望与现实分歧的地方 也是我的问题所在
So what's the problem?
那么问题是什么
The problem is when I run this for loop and I'm comparing from negative 2 all the way up to 2, I'm comparing all the dogs to my left and my right, I'm also comparing the dog to myself.
问题在于当我运行这个for循环时 我从-2一直比较到2 我在比较所有左边和右边的狗 我还在比较自己和狗
And then this line of code says, well, you're always going to be greater than or equal to yourself, so isBiggest always gets set to false.
然后这行代码说 嗯 你始终大于或等于自己 所以isBiggest总是被设置为false
Aha, there it is.
啊哈 就是这样
And so again, I kind of skipped over some steps.
所以 我又跳过了一些步骤
The important thing is not this specific piece of code, but just the idea of being able to get comfortable with this debugger.
重要的不是这段特定的代码 而是只是能够熟悉这个调试器的想法
So in case you're curious,
如果你感兴趣的话
You're all mumbling so much, I'm sure you're all talking about how to fix this.
你们都嘟囔着这么多 我敢肯定你们都在讨论如何修复这个问题
The way to fix it is to add something like, well, if the comparing x is equal to 0, I'm comparing to myself, I don't want to do that, so maybe I'll just skip to the next iteration of the for loop.
修复的方法是添加类似的东西 嗯 如果比较的 x 等于 0 我是在与自己比较 我不想这样做 所以也许我会直接跳到 for 循环的下一次迭代
Now if I run it, hopefully I get the 20 and the 22 that I was hoping for.
现在如果我运行它 希望我得到我希望的 20 和 22
Hold on, I have one more thing to show you.
等等 我还有一件事要给你看
Okay, all of this is to say
好的 所有这些都是为了说
It's okay if you don't totally know how to use the debugger yet.
如果你还不太知道如何使用调试器 没关系
The important thing is not the specifics, but just that you're able to get more familiar with it.
重要的不是具体细节 而只是你能更熟悉它
I would say, and this is the thing that I think is important from this like brand new debugger unit, I would say being able to use the debugger is the difference between spending like one hour and 10 hours on an assignment.
我想说 而我认为从这种全新的调试器单元中重要的是 能够使用调试器是在任务上花费一小时和十小时之间的区别
So this is what you really want to get comfortable with.
这就是你真正想要熟悉的内容
Hopefully that scared you a little bit into using it.
希望这会让你有点害怕开始使用它
Here are some slides if you want to, but you all want to go home.
这里有一些幻灯片 如果你想要的话 但你们都想回家
So you can go home and I'll see you on Monday.
你们可以回家了 周一见
Okay, bye.
好的 再见